Subtitle Provide by dramacool.asia Translator [Admin.@YNG]
تم توفير الترجمة بواسطة مترجم dramacool.asia [Admin.@YNG]
[Echoes of the Self]
[أصداء الذات]
Princess Fu Wei,
الأميرة فو وي,
why are you here?
لماذا انت هنا؟
Why did you lie?
لماذا كذبت؟
Why betray your mother?
لماذا تخون والدتك؟
Why do things you'd regret?
لماذا تفعل أشياء تندم عليها؟
In what capacity are you speaking to me like this?
بأي صفة تتحدث معي بهذه الطريقة؟
As the noble Princess of Daqing
بصفتي الأميرة النبيلة من داتشينغ
or as my cousin whom I've never met?
أو مثل ابن عمي الذي لم أقابله قط؟
I know Madam Cui has been oppressing you all these years.
أعلم أن السيدة كوي كانت تضطهدك كل هذه السنوات.
But however hard and dangerous it's been,
ولكن مهما كان الأمر صعبًا وخطيرًا،
you shouldn't betray your own mother.
لا ينبغي لك أن تخون والدتك.
Don't you know
ألا تعلم؟
the risk of
خطر
bargaining with a tiger?
المساومة مع النمر؟
Everyone understands that.
الجميع يفهم ذلك.
But does knowing that
ولكن هل معرفة ذلك
actually help people survive
في الواقع مساعدة الناس على البقاء على قيد الحياة
or help them rise to power?
أو مساعدتهم على الوصول إلى السلطة؟
I can protect you.
انا استطيع حمايتك
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو.
But you're here for a political marriage.
لكنك هنا من أجل زواج سياسي.
You may protect us today,
يمكنك حمايتنا اليوم،
but once you leave the Zhou's Mansion,
ولكن بمجرد مغادرة قصر تشو،
how will my mother and I survive here?
كيف سأعيش أنا وأمي هنا؟
My mother needs more rest.
والدتي تحتاج إلى مزيد من الراحة.
Please leave, Your Highness.
من فضلك إرحل يا صاحب السمو.
Perhaps I shouldn't blame my past self who's been lost in confusion
ربما لا ينبغي لي أن ألوم ذاتي السابقة التي ضاعت في الارتباك
and unable to find a way out.
وغير قادرين على إيجاد طريقة للخروج.
I need to figure everything out quickly
أحتاج إلى معرفة كل شيء بسرعة
and find a way
وإيجاد طريقة
to take Mother and Xi away.
لأخذ الأم و شي بعيدا.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
your ginseng soup is here.
حساء الجينسنغ الخاص بك هنا.
Don't move.
.لا تتحرك
What are you really after?
ماذا تريد حقا؟
Why make me impersonate the Princess?
لماذا تجعلني انتحل شخصية الأميرة؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
what are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
You are the Princess of Daqing.
أنت أميرة داتشينغ.
Still won't tell the truth?
مازلت لا تقول الحقيقة؟
Then don't blame me for showing no mercy.
إذن لا تلومني على عدم إظهار الرحمة.
I'll tell you.
سأخبرك.
That day when you collapsed by the roadside,
في ذلك اليوم الذي انهارت فيه على جانب الطريق،
Princess saved you.
الأميرة أنقذتك.
When you woke up, you were confused
عندما استيقظت كنت مرتبكًا
and had forgotten everything that happened in your past.
وقد نسيت كل ما حدث في الماضي.
Your appearance happens to be similar to Princess's,
يبدو أن مظهرك مشابه لمظهر الأميرة،
so Princess
لذا يا أميرة
had you take her place.
لقد أخذت مكانها.
Your Princess want me to die in her place?
هل تريد أميرتك أن أموت في مكانها؟
Princess simply didn't want this political marriage.
الأميرة ببساطة لم ترغب في هذا الزواج السياسي.
The encounter with bandits at the posthouse that day
اللقاء مع قطاع الطرق في مكتب البريد ذلك اليوم
was truly an accident.
لقد كان حادثًا حقيقيًا.
Princess knew nothing about it.
الأميرة لم تكن تعلم شيئا عن هذا الأمر.
Where is Princess now?
أين الأميرة الآن؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف.
It's just that...
إنه فقط ذلك...
Princess told me to keep an eye on you.
لقد طلبت مني الأميرة أن أراقبك.
Princess and I are not the same person.
أنا والأميرة لسنا نفس الشخص.
How can I replace her?
كيف يمكنني استبدالها؟
The women of the Daqing royal family
نساء العائلة المالكة داتشينغ
all wear veils in public.
الجميع يرتدون الحجاب في الأماكن العامة.
Except for their personal servants,
باستثناء خدمهم الشخصيين،
no one knows what they look like.
لا أحد يعرف كيف يبدوا.
Besides, Princess has the marriage documents.
وبالإضافة إلى ذلك، الأميرة لديها وثائق الزواج.
As long as I stay with you,
طالما بقيت معك،
you are the Princess.
أنت الأميرة.
Your name is Linglan, right?
اسمك لينجلان، أليس كذلك؟
From now on, you'll follow me.
من الآن فصاعدا، سوف تتبعني.
However your princess treated you before,
ومع ذلك فإن أميرتك تعاملك من قبل،
that's how I'll treat you.
هكذا سأعاملك
But if you dare tell anyone about this impersonation,
ولكن إذا تجرأت على إخبار أي شخص عن هذا التقليد،
I won't spare your life.
لن ابقي على حياتك
Yes.
نعم.
Given how things stand,
بالنظر إلى الوضع الحالي للأمور،
I have to take advantage of the identity of Princess of Daqing,
يجب عليّ الاستفادة من هوية أميرة داتشينغ،
so that I won't repeat the same mistake.
حتى لا أكرر نفس الخطأ.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
do you mean to take my life?
هل تقصد أن تأخذ حياتي؟
How do the guards in the royal escort team
كيف يعمل الحراس في فريق الحراسة الملكية؟
compare to you
مقارنة بك
in martial arts?
في الفنون القتالية؟
I've heard
لقد سمعت
that Daqing's warriors are all top-notch fighters.
أن محاربي داتشينغ جميعهم مقاتلون من الطراز الأول.
Their martial arts
فنونهم القتالية
are certainly better than mine.
بالتأكيد أفضل مني.
They were all top-notch fighters,
لقد كانوا جميعًا مقاتلين من الطراز الأول،
yet they were killed with a single strike,
ولكنهم قتلوا بضربة واحدة.
without even signs of resistance.
بدون حتى أي علامات للمقاومة.
This clearly shows
وهذا يظهر بوضوح
how formidable the killer is.
كم هو قاتل رهيب.
But
لكن
who would dare
من يجرؤ؟
to assassinate the princess sent for marriage alliance?
لاغتيال الأميرة المرسلة للزواج من التحالف؟
This could seriously affect relations between the two states.
وقد يؤثر هذا بشكل خطير على العلاقات بين الدولتين.
Father,
أب،
I believe
انا أؤمن
we must not agree to Daqing's marriage alliance.
لا يجب علينا أن نوافق على زواج داتشينغ.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
since Daqing has shown goodwill,
منذ أن أظهرت داتشينغ حسن النية،
why resort to conflict?
لماذا اللجوء إلى الصراع؟
Lord Liu,
اللورد ليو،
a temporary war
حرب مؤقتة
is to secure lasting peace.
الهدف هو ضمان السلام الدائم.
Don't you understand that?
ألا تفهم ذلك؟
Regarding this marriage alliance,
وفيما يتعلق بهذا التحالف الزواجي،
I believe
انا أؤمن
the benefits outweigh the drawbacks.
الفوائد تفوق العيوب.
This matter needs no further discussion.
هذه المسألة لا تحتاج إلى مزيد من المناقشة.
Your Majesty is wise.
جلالتك حكيم.
This matter is indeed complicated.
إن هذه المسألة معقدة بالفعل.
I must find out who's behind this.
يجب أن أعرف من وراء هذا.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
we can't find any more clues from those dead bodies.
لم نتمكن من العثور على أي أدلة أخرى من تلك الجثث.
What should we
ماذا يجب علينا
do next?
ماذا افعل بعد ذلك؟
Since we can't find more clues
نظرًا لأننا لا نستطيع العثور على المزيد من الأدلة
from the dead,
من بين الأموات،
we must look among the living.
علينا أن ننظر بين الأحياء.
[Zhou's Mansion]
[قصر تشو]
She seems somewhat similar
يبدو أنها مشابهة إلى حد ما
to the person in my dreams.
للشخص في أحلامي.
Yan.
نعم.
Prince Yan.
الأمير يان.
Princess.
أميرة.
The old wound on your left arm is acting up again.
الجرح القديم على ذراعك اليسرى يتفاقم مرة أخرى.
How did she know?
كيف عرفت؟
And why does she care so much?
ولماذا تهتم بهذا القدر؟
Have we met before?
هل التقينا من قبل؟
No.
لا.
If we've never met,
إذا لم نلتقي أبدًا،
then why
ثم لماذا
do you
هل أنت؟
know so much
اعرف الكثير
about Yunrui's affairs?
حول شؤون يونروي؟
You must have carefully arranged
يجب أن تكون قد رتبت بعناية
for this marriage alliance
لهذا التحالف الزواجي
and have a chosen husband in mind.
ويكون في ذهني زوج مختار.
Are you suggesting
هل تقترح؟
that my carefully selected future husband
أن زوجي المستقبلي الذي اخترته بعناية
is you?
هل انت؟
Could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
she wants to marry me?
هل تريد الزواج مني؟
I not only know about your left arm injury,
أنا لا أعرف فقط عن إصابة ذراعك اليسرى،
but I also know
ولكنني أعلم أيضا
that the Crown Prince's childhood sweetheart
أن حبيبة طفولة ولي العهد
is the eldest daughter of the Zhou family,
هي الابنة الكبرى لعائلة تشو،
and even what kind of women His Majesty prefers.
وحتى ما هو نوع النساء الذي يفضله جلالته؟
Doesn't that make me more suspicious?
ألا يجعلني هذا أكثر شكًا؟
I came here for a marriage alliance.
لقد جئت إلى هنا من أجل الزواج.
What's so weird about understanding the personalities
ما هو الغريب في فهم الشخصيات
and preferences of the royal family?
وتفضيلات العائلة المالكة؟
Do I have to wait until the veil is lifted
هل يجب علي الانتظار حتى يتم رفع الحجاب
in the bridal sedan
في سيارة العروس
to find out who I'm marrying?
لأعرف من سأتزوج؟
It seems
يبدو أنه
I overthought this.
لقد فكرت في هذا الأمر كثيرًا.
Regarding the incident at the posthouse,
بخصوص الحادثة التي وقعت في مكتب البريد،
I have sent people to investigate it thoroughly.
لقد أرسلت أشخاصًا للتحقيق في الأمر بدقة.
Except for you
إلا أنت
and your maid Linglan,
وخادمتك لينجلان،
everyone else
الجميع
was killed by the bandits,
قُتل على يد قطاع الطرق،
with no survivors.
بدون أي ناجين.
But Princess,
ولكن يا أميرة
why don't you show any grief?
لماذا لا تظهر أي حزن؟
How
كيف
should grief be shown?
هل يجب إظهار الحزن؟
They were all loyal servants
وكانوا جميعا خدما مخلصين
who accompanied me throughout the journey.
الذي رافقني طوال الرحلة.
Now that they're dead,
الآن وقد ماتوا،
what I can do
ماذا يمكنني أن أفعل
is not to wallow in self-pity,
لا ينبغي أن نغرق في الشفقة على الذات،
but to seek justice for them.
بل السعي لتحقيق العدالة لهم.
Prince Yan,
الأمير يان
isn't that right?
أليس هذا صحيحا؟
But the assassins weren't some ordinary bandits,
لكن القتلة لم يكونوا مجرد قطاع طرق عاديين،
but highly skilled martial artists.
لكنهم فنانين قتاليين ذوي مهارات عالية.
It seems everything
يبدو أن كل شيء
was carefully premeditated.
لقد تم التخطيط لها بعناية.
Premeditated?
مُخطط له مسبقًا؟
Could it be that Princess of Daqing's death in the previous life
هل يمكن أن يكون سبب وفاة أميرة داتشينغ في الحياة السابقة؟
wasn't an accident at all?
ولم يكن حادثا على الإطلاق؟
Princess,
أميرة،
have you thought of something?
هل فكرت في شيء؟
There was nothing
لم يكن هناك شيء
unusual along the way.
غير عادي على طول الطريق.
If you have the ability,
إذا كانت لديك القدرة،
you can investigate yourself.
يمكنك التحقيق بنفسك.
But...
لكن...
Did you come today
هل أتيت اليوم
to interrogate a prisoner?
لاستجواب سجين؟
I'm here to take you to the Court of Imperial Sacrifices
أنا هنا لأخذك إلى محكمة التضحيات الإمبراطورية
for registration.
للتسجيل.
The carriage is ready.
العربة جاهزة.
Please, Princess.
من فضلك يا أميرة.
Don't touch it.
لا تلمسه.
It hurts.
إنه يؤلمني.
Mother,
الأم،
how did you get hurt so badly?
كيف تم إصابتك بهذا الشكل السيئ؟
If you
إذا كنت
hadn't come back,
لم يعد
I'd have been beaten to death.
لقد تعرضت للضرب حتى الموت.
Every day
كل يوم
you think about being with the Crown Prince.
أنت تفكر في أن تكون مع ولي العهد.
How could you care about my safety?
كيف يمكنك أن تهتم بسلامتي؟
I went to the mountains to gather herbs.
ذهبت إلى الجبال لجمع الأعشاب.
His Highness was worried about my safety,
لقد كان سموه قلقًا على سلامتي،
so he accompanied me.
فرافقني.
His Highness truly cares for you.
صاحب السمو يهتم بك حقًا.
You must not disappoint his sincere feelings.
لا يجب أن تخيب مشاعره الصادقة.
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
you should
يجب عليك
get married soon,
تزوج قريبا
and put my mind at ease.
وأطمئن نفسي.
His Highness truly cares for me.
سموه يهتم بي حقًا.
Does that mean I must marry him?
هل هذا يعني أنني يجب أن أتزوجه؟
When His Highness becomes Emperor one day,
عندما يصبح سموه إمبراطورًا في أحد الأيام،
he will surely have thousands of concubines.
فإنه سيكون له بالتأكيد آلاف من الجواري.
I don't want to fight over a man with a crowd of women.
لا أريد القتال على رجل مع حشد من النساء.
Foolish!
غبي!
Mother,
الأم،
please rest well.
من فضلك إرتاح جيدا.
You're really confused!
أنت مرتبك حقًا!
So many women are eagerly pursuing
الكثير من النساء يسعين بشغف
that position of Empress above thousands.
هذا هو موقف الإمبراطورة فوق الآلاف.
Only you
أنت فقط
fail to see its value.
فشل في رؤية قيمته.
We already had those two, mother and daughter, at home
لقد كان لدينا بالفعل هاتين الأم وابنتها في المنزل
who were eyesores.
الذين كانوا قبيحي المنظر.
Now suddenly a Daqing Princess shows up,
والآن تظهر فجأة أميرة داتشينغ،
and your father takes her side.
وأبوك يقف إلى جانبها.
He listened to her,
لقد استمع لها
and even punished me.
وحتى عاقبني.
Yao,
لهم،
you must put more effort into this.
يجب عليك بذل المزيد من الجهد في هذا.
If you don't try harder,
إذا لم تحاول بجهد أكبر،
His Highness will be taken by someone else.
سموه سوف يأخذه شخص آخر.
Someone who can be taken away
شخص يمكن أن يؤخذ بعيدا
isn't truly devoted.
ليس مخلصًا حقًا.
I don't care about that.
لا يهمني ذلك.
By the way, Mother.
بالمناسبة يا أمي.
Princess of Daqing has a noble status
أميرة داتشينغ لها مكانة نبيلة
and is also Madam Wang's distant relative.
وهو أيضًا قريب بعيد للسيدة وانج.
If you keep opposing her,
إذا واصلت معارضتها،
aren't you just asking for trouble?
ألا تطلب المتاعب فقط؟
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
you shouldn't take everything so seriously.
لا ينبغي عليك أن تأخذ كل شيء على محمل الجد.
Madam.
سيدتي.
[Cicada Notebook]
[دفتر السيكادا]
Ruoxi, you're here.
رووكسي، أنت هنا.
Big Mother,
الأم الكبيرة
you wanted to see me?
هل تريد رؤيتي؟
Well, Ruoxi,
حسنًا، رووكسي،
I have
أملك
truly underestimated you.
لقد قللت من شأنك حقًا.
To save your mother,
لإنقاذ والدتك،
you were even willing to abandon your maternal family.
حتى أنك كنت على استعداد للتخلي عن عائلتك من جهة أمك.
Did you summon me
هل استدعيتني؟
just to talk about this?
فقط للحديث عن هذا؟
Of course not.
بالطبع لا.
I'm here to give you
انا هنا لأعطيك
and your mother
وأمك
a way to survive.
طريقة للبقاء على قيد الحياة.
I want that Princess of Daqing
أريد تلك الأميرة من داتشينغ
gone from this world.
رحلت عن هذا العالم.
You want to hire someone to kill her?
هل تريد أن تستأجر شخصًا ليقتلها؟
What price are you offering?
ما هو السعر الذي تقدمه؟
Have you picked the wrong person?
هل اخترت الشخص الخطأ؟
What if
ماذا إذا
it's your mother's life at stake?
هل حياة والدتك على المحك؟
I wonder if you think
أتساءل عما إذا كنت تعتقد
that's enough.
هذا يكفي.
This poison mixed in tea
هذا السم المخلوط بالشاي
has a fragrant aroma
له رائحة عطرة
and a lingering taste.
وطعم باقي.
The symptoms of poisoning
أعراض التسمم
resemble tuberculosis.
تشبه مرض السل.
At best,
في أحسن الأحوال،
she'll be bedridden.
ستكون طريحة الفراش.
At worst,
في أسوأ الأحوال،
she won't survive.
انها لن تنجو.
You are cousins.
أنتم أبناء عمومة.
You'll have plenty of opportunities.
سيكون لديك الكثير من الفرص.
Of course,
بالطبع،
if you're unwilling,
إذا كنت غير راغب،
I certainly won't force you.
أنا بالتأكيد لن أجبرك.
It's just
إنه فقط
a pity.
ومثير للشفقة.
Your mother
والدتك
is already frail,
هو بالفعل ضعيف،
and now she's been beaten.
والآن تعرضت للضرب.
Who knows
من يعلم
how many days she has left?
كم يوم باقي لها؟
Mother,
الأم،
I'm well aware of
أنا على علم جيد بذلك
Madam Cui's wicked intentions.
نوايا السيدة كوي الشريرة.
She simply wants to use me
إنها تريد فقط أن تستخدمني
to poison Princess Fu Wei
لتسميم الأميرة فو وي
to eliminate her threat
للقضاء على تهديدها
and then place all
ثم ضع كل شيء
the blame on me.
اللوم علي.
Killing two birds with one stone.
قتل عصفورين بحجر واحد.
Mother.
الأم.
If anything happens to me,
إذا حدث لي أي شيء،
please don't worry,
من فضلك لا تقلق
and don't blame me.
ولا تلوموني.
The current Princess Fu Wei is fake?
هل الأميرة فو وي الحالية مزيفة؟
Yes.
نعم.
Master, do you want me to kill her?
سيدي هل تريد مني أن أقتلها؟
No.
لا.
Hold your position
حافظ على موقفك
and wait for my instructions.
وانتظر تعليماتي.
Master,
يتقن،
I...
أنا...
It's time now.
لقد حان الوقت الآن.
Take it.
خذها.
Thank you, Master.
شكرا لك يا سيدي.
Xi,
شي،
come with me.
تعال معي.
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
I should be asking you.
ينبغي لي أن أسألك.
What are you going to do?
ما كنت تنوي القيام به؟
I'm bringing ginseng tea to Big Mother
سأحضر شاي الجينسنغ إلى الأم الكبيرة
to apologize for offending her earlier.
للاعتذار عن الإساءة إليها في وقت سابق.
Your Highness, why are you so nervous?
صاحب السمو، لماذا أنت متوتر هكذا؟
Are you really apologizing to her
هل تعتذر لها حقا؟
or setting a trap yourself
أو وضع فخ لنفسك
to frame her?
لتأطيرها؟
I don't understand what you mean.
لا أفهم ماذا تقصد.
You suspect I'm poisoning Big Mother?
هل تشك بأنني أسمم الأم الكبيرة؟
You're planning to poison yourself.
أنت تخطط لتسميم نفسك.
You know with Madam Cui's suspicion of you,
كما تعلمون، مع شكوك السيدة كوي فيك،
you can't easily poison her.
لا يمكنك تسميمها بسهولة.
So you can only poison yourself
لذلك لا يمكنك إلا تسميم نفسك
and then frame her for it.
ومن ثم يتهمها بذلك.
Big Mother...
الأم الكبيرة...
How cruel of you.
كم أنت قاسي!
You've poisoned me.
لقد سممتني.
You wretched girl!
يا فتاة بائسة!
How dare you frame Madam!
كيف تجرؤ على تأطير السيدة!
About this poisoning incident,
حول حادثة التسمم هذه،
let's just forget about it.
دعونا ننسى هذا الأمر.
Take care of yourself.
اعتنِ بنفسك.
Father—
أب؟؟؟
I said,
قلت
forget it.
انسى ذلك.
Even if you're willing to risk your life
حتى لو كنت على استعداد للمخاطرة بحياتك
to drag her down with you,
لتسحبها معك إلى الأسفل،
you should understand that
يجب عليك أن تفهم ذلك
in this Zhou's Mansion,
في قصر تشو هذا،
no one will protect you
لا أحد سوف يحميك
or help you.
أو مساعدتك.
Your life
حياتك
means absolutely nothing.
لا يعني شيئا على الإطلاق.
Even if I know this is like a moth to a flame,
حتى لو كنت أعلم أن هذا مثل الفراشة بالنسبة للهب،
it's the only plan I could think of.
إنها الخطة الوحيدة التي أستطيع التفكير فيها.
Your Highness, do you know
صاحب السمو هل تعلم
this poison
هذا السم
was originally meant for your tea, on Madam Cui's order?
هل كان المقصود في الأصل أن يتم تقديمه لشاي الخاص بك، بناءً على طلب السيدة كوي؟
She wanted to kill you by my hand.
أرادت قتلك بيدي.
Do you have any
هل لديك أي
other option besides desperate measures?
هل هناك خيار آخر غير التدابير اليائسة؟
Neither of us will die.
لن يموت أي منا.
Your Highness, what brings you here today?
صاحب السمو، ما الذي أتى بك إلى هنا اليوم؟
Mrs. Zhou,
السيدة تشو،
today Xi brought me some new tea.
اليوم أحضر لي شي بعض الشاي الجديد.
Since I've been disturbing you here for so long,
نظرًا لأنني أزعجتك هنا لفترة طويلة،
I thought
اعتقدت
I'd bring it to you as a small gift.
سأحضره لك كهدية صغيرة.
This tea was brought by Ruoxi?
هل تم جلب هذا الشاي بواسطة رووكسي؟
Yes.
نعم.
Mrs. Zhou,
السيدة تشو،
please try it.
من فضلك جربه.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
Xi said
وقال شي
this tea
هذا الشاي
has a wonderful aroma
له رائحة رائعة
and a lingering aftertaste.
وطعم باقي.
Please have a taste, Mrs. Zhou.
من فضلك تذوقي، السيدة تشو.
Recently,
حديثاً،
I've been feeling unsettled
لقد كنت أشعر بعدم الاستقرار
and can't sleep
ولا أستطيع النوم
at night.
في الليل.
The doctor said
قال الطبيب
I shouldn't drink strong tea.
لا ينبغي لي أن أشرب الشاي القوي.
Can't sleep at night?
لا تستطيع النوم في الليل؟
Could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
you've done something unconscionable to harm someone's life?
هل قمت بشيء غير مقبول لإيذاء حياة شخص ما؟
I was just joking.
لقد كنت أمزح فقط.
There's no need to be so nervous.
لا داعي لأن تكون متوترًا جدًا.
It's just that
إنه فقط ذلك
this tea
هذا الشاي
is what I
هو ما انا
have bestowed upon you.
لقد أنعمت عليك.
So you
لذا انت
must drink it.
يجب أن أشربه.